tipandtrick.net 2011-06-02

# Privacy Policy » Tip and Trick

Thanks for visiting Tip and Trick. Your privacy on the Internet is of the utmost importance to us. At Tip and Trick, we want to make your experience online satisfying and safe.

Because we gather certain types of information about our users, we feel you should fully understand our policy and the terms and conditions surrounding the capture and use of that information. The following privacy statement discloses the information gathering and dissemination practices for Tip and Trick.

**Website Usage Tracking**

As with most standard Web servers, Tip and Trick Web server tracks user traffic patterns throughout all of our sites. In addition, we may use third party tracker to collect more traffic information. The information tracked includes Internet Protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, MIME type, Internet service provider (ISP), referring and exit pages, platform type, date and time stamp, and number of clicks. IP addresses are not linked to personally identifiable information, and Tip and Trick does not correlate this information with data about individual users.

This information allows us to better tailor our content to readers’ needs, analyze trends, administer the site, track user’s movement in the aggregate, gather broad demographic information for aggregate use and to help our advertisers and sponsors better understand the demographics of our audience. Because Tip and Trick derives its revenue mainly from sponsorships and advertising, providing such aggregated demographic data is essential to keeping our service free to users. Under no circumstances does Tip and Trick divulge any information about an individual user to a third party, except to comply with applicable law or valid legal process or to protect the personal safety of our users or the public.

**Cookies**

Tip and Trick may place a text file called a “cookie” in the browser files of your computer. The cookie itself does not contain Personal Information although it will enable us to relate your use of this site to information that you have specifically and knowingly provided. But the only personal information a cookie can contain is information you supply yourself, such as in Comments form and login information. A cookie can’t read data off your hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Tip and Trick also uses cookies to track user traffic patterns, sometimes via third party tracker (as described above). 

Beside, our advertising delivery business partners use cookies to better track ad impressions and click rates. However, we have no access to or control over these cookies, once we have given permission for them to set cookies for advertising. These cookies, normally added by ads, and information collected is by outside advertising companies, and we do not have access to this information. We work with the advertising develiery companies such as Google AdSense, Chitika, Tirbal Fusion, etc and other technology partners such as StatCounter. Please check their websites for respective privacy policies. 

You can refuse cookies by turning them off in your browser. If you’ve set your browser to warn you before accepting cookies, you will receive the warning message with each cookie. You do not need to have cookies turned on to use this site. However, you do need cookies to participate actively in message boards, forums, polling and surveys.

**Children**

Consistent with the Federal Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998 (COPPA), we will never knowingly request personally identifiable information from anyone under the age of 13 without requesting parental consent.

**Electronic Newsletters (Dispatches or Update Subscribes)**

Tip and Trick offers a free electronic newsletter to users through FeedBurner service. FeedBurner gathers the email addresses of users who voluntarily subscribe, which Tip and Trick also has acccess to. Tip and Trick will never shares newsletter mailing list with any third parties, including advertisers, sponsors or partners. These email addresses collected are solely meant for newsletter delivery. For Privacy Policy of FeedBurner, check out their website. Users may remove themselves from this mailing list by following the link provided in every newsletter that points users to the subscription management page. Users can also subscribe to the newsletters any time on this site.

**Message Boards (Forums)**

Users of the site’s Message Boards and Forums must register separately to participate in the discussions and post messages. Registration to forum services is free of charge). Visitor needn’t register to visit the site. During registration the user is required to supply a username, password, and email address.

**Polling**

We may offer interactive polls to users so they can easily share their opinions with other users and see what our audience thinks about important issues. Opinions or other responses to polls are aggregated and are not identifiable to any particular user. Tip and Trick may use a system to “tag” users after they have voted, so they can vote only once on a particular question. This tag is not correlated with information about individual users.

**Surveys**

Tip and Trick may occasionally conduct user surveys to better target our content to our audience. We sometimes share the aggregated demographic information in these surveys with our sponsors, advertisers and partners. We never share any of this information about specific individuals with any third party.

**YOUR CONSENT**

By using this site, you consent to the collection and use of this information by Tip and Trick. If we decide to change our privacy policy, we will post those changes on this page so that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances we disclose it.

  * [Free Online Phonemyphone Service Helps Locating Misplaced Mobile Phone](http://www.tipandtrick.net/2008/free-online-phonemyphone-service-helps-locating-misplaced-mobile-phone/ "Permanent Link: Free Online Phonemyphone Service Helps Locating Misplaced Mobile Phone")
  * [Free Genuine License Code for Privacy Guardian by Signing Up PC Tools Newsletter](http://www.tipandtrick.net/2008/free-genuine-license-code-for-privacy-guardian-by-signing-up-pc-tools-newsletter/ "Permanent Link: Free Genuine License Code for Privacy Guardian by Signing Up PC Tools Newsletter")
  * [Enable Lock Pages in Memory to Prevent Database Paging to Disk](http://www.tipandtrick.net/2008/enable-lock-pages-in-memory-to-prevent-database-paging-to-disk/ "Permanent Link: Enable Lock Pages in Memory to Prevent Database Paging to Disk")
  * [Steganos Security Suite 2007 Full Version Free Download and Serial Number](http://www.tipandtrick.net/2008/steganos-security-suite-2007-full-version-free-download-and-serial-number/ "Permanent Link: Steganos Security Suite 2007 Full Version Free Download and Serial Number")
  * [How to Change the Default Setting for Power Button Action in Windows 7](http://www.tipandtrick.net/2010/how-to-change-the-default-setting-for-power-button-action-in-windows-7/ "Permanent Link: How to Change the Default Setting for Power Button Action in Windows 7")
  * [Not a Hack: Lahore Electric Supply Companies (LESCO) Website Privacy Leaks](http://www.tipandtrick.net/2008/not-a-hack-lahore-electric-supply-companies-lesco-website-privacy-leaks/ "Permanent Link: Not a Hack: Lahore Electric Supply Companies \(LESCO\) Website Privacy Leaks")
  * [How to Disable Windows Vista CD/DVD Disc Burning/Recording Function](http://www.tipandtrick.net/2008/how-to-disable-windows-vista-cddvd-disc-burningrecording-function/ "Permanent Link: How to Disable Windows Vista CD/DVD Disc Burning/Recording Function")
